普段は 緊張してるから
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
バカヤロー 何 考えてやがんだ
何てことをしてくれた 何てことを
You idiot! What the hell are you thinking?!
How could you do this?! How?!
結局 私は…
In the end, is it...
私は ここにいてもいいのかな
Is it okay if I stay here?
In the end, time unforgiving
Will draw the blood of covenant
Everything scatters, leaving void
But we're here for the greater good
crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
The stage with our careless justice
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
Under this sky, oh so dear
We're fighting for the future
Until you like at least one thing
September came and brought the new semester with it.
９月に入り ２学期が始まっていた
"Forget about Kimijima Kou."
君島コウのことは 忘れなさい
"Why should I forget about him?"
忘れなさいって どういうことだよ
いい？ 分かったわね
"Okay? I know you get it."
Call ended
Was that supposed to be some kind of a warning?
警告のつもり
余計 気になるんだけど
It just piqued my interest even more...
And this means that Misa and Kimijima Kou...
ていうか ミサ姉 やっぱり君島コウのこと…
Minamitane Folk Museum
I will now tell you the flag for report no. 4.
レポートナンバー４のフラグをお伝えします
Minamitane Folk Museum
Kimijima report no. 4 release conditions
Find Kimijima report no. 3.
Upload rocket launch photographs taken from four suggested spots in Tanegashima.
One: Find Kimijima report no. 3.
１ 君島レポートナンバー３を発見している
Two: Upload rocket launch photographs taken from four suggested spots in Tanegashima.
２ 種子島の４カ所のお薦めポイントから撮影した
ロケットの打ち上げ写真を『居ル夫。』にアップロード
Three: Fire at least one shot with a geotagged matchlock.
３ ジオタグを付与した火縄銃を１発以上試射する
Four: Activate Gojiro at the Robot Clinic.
４ ロボクリニックに保管されている五二郎君の起動スイッチを押す
What's Gojiro?
五二郎君って 何だ
ロボクリニックってことは…
If it's at the Robot Clinic though...
ちゅうも～く
Attention!
Starting today, we'll be building GunPro-2 here!
今日から ここでガンつく２を組み立てるよ
Huh? Here?
ここ 貸してもらえるんですか
We can use this place?
Yes. It should be fine as long as someone from the staff is here with you.
職員の誰かが監督しているかぎり 問題ないと思うよ
There are cranes too.
クレーンもあるし 空けたままにしておくのももったいないからね
It'd be a shame to just let this place collect dust.
This time we can build it standing!
今回は 立てた状態で組み上げていけるんだよ
I'm so excited!
たぎってきた
We haven't even decided on its propulsion yet.
まだ 駆動システムも決まってないんですよ
I'd say we should talk to Doc about that...
そこは できればドクに相談したいんだよねぇ
And about... that too.
モノ…のことも含めてさ
You still haven't given up?
まだ諦めてないんですか
But Gunvarrel's reviews plummeted after the last episode got leaked.
だって あの最終回の流出騒ぎで
『ガンヴァレル』の評判ががた落ちなんだよ
We must build GunPro-2 and do something about that!
うちらが ガンつく２を完成させて何とかしなきゃ
What's wrong, Jun?
どうしたの ジュン
Excuse me!
ごめんなさい
Sure...
Yes?
はい お父さん
Ah, Dad?
I'm with my friends.
今 ちょっと 友達と…
Eh?!
Tanegashima Public Hospital
Intensive Care
Fujita Tetsuharu
Are you looking for something?
何か ご用ですか
Um, uh... I'm Mr. Fujita's granddaughter...
あっ あの…私…
ふ…藤田のおじいちゃんの孫の…
…ってくれ
Please...
帰って…帰って…もらってくれ
Please... make her leave...
Jun!
ジュン
How's Doc?
ドク どうだった
あ…会えなかったから
I couldn't see him...
You couldn't?
会えなかったって
He can't even have visitors?
まさか 面会謝絶
No...
ううん
He wouldn't see me.
会って…もらえなくて
Huh?
You met Doc?
ドクと会った
Yeah. I went to see him yesterday.
おお 昨日 見舞いに行ってな
I don't get it. He wouldn't see Jun the other day.
何で おととい行ったとき ジュンは会えなかったのに
で どんな様子だった
How is he?
He's gotten very weak.
だいぶ弱ってるみたいだったぞ
His body, of course, but also his feelings.
体もそうだが 気持ちの方がな
His feelings?
気持ち
I'm thinking of closing the shop.
店を畳もうと思ってる
潮時さ
But...
そんな…
It's unusual to see you here.
珍しいね こんな所にいるなんて
Are you depressed that you don't have the courage to visit him?
病院に行く勇気がなくて落ち込んでるってところ
That's not...
そういうわけじゃ…
I wasn't very close to grandpa Fujita anyway.
もともと 藤田のおじいちゃんとは疎遠だったし
Then--
じゃあ…
I'm... thinking of quitting the Robotics Club...
私
ロボ部 辞めようかなって思ってて
Oh, why am I not surprised?
そうきたか
弱ったな
Anyway, how about we go inside?
取りあえず 中 入らない
まったく 口が軽い
Geez, you can't keep a secret.
Sorry, I just...
いや つい…
I really hope you're not looking into strange things again.
また おかしなことに首 突っ込んでるんじゃないだろうね
Not really.
別に それより 情報 手に入ったんでしょ
More importantly, you've got some intel for me, right?
Doc was a NASDA mechanic, you see.
ドクは元ＮＡＳＤＡの技術者でね
ＮＡＳＤＡって ＪＡＸＡのもとになったところ
NASDA? You mean the precursor to JAXA?
Yeah.
When the Robot Clinic was opened 18 years ago, it was a shop for kids
１８年前できたばかりのロボクリニックは子供のための店で
with robots Doc built lined up in front of it.
店の前には ドクの造ったロボットたちが並んでた
I remember it well too.
私も よく覚えてるよ
Back then, Doc always said that robots are the friends of humans.
当時 ドクがよく言ってた
「ロボットは人間の友達だ」って
I can't even believe that.
信じられない
で そのロボットたちは 今…
What happened to those robots?
They're sleeping in the Robot Clinic.
ロボクリニックの奥で眠ってるよ
Why?
何で
There was an accident.
事故があったのさ
I...
私 し…失礼します
Excuse me!
ジュンちゃん
Jun?
11 years ago, a robot fell down and hurt a child.
１１年前 子供がロボットの下敷きになってケガをしたんだ
It was Doc's granddaughter, Daitoku Junna.
ドクの孫娘 大徳淳和がね
Hello, my name is Yoshiro!
コンニチハ ボクノナマエハ ヨシロウ
I'm your robot friend!
ミンナノ オトモダチロボットダヨ
Hey, let's shake hands!
ネエ アクシュシヨウヨ
You're not my friend!
友達…じゃない
Hello, my name is Yoshiro!
あなたなんか 友達じゃ…
You're not... not my friend!
Hey, let's shake hands!
バカヤロー 何 考えてやがんだ
You idiot! What the hell are you thinking?!
How could you do this?! How?!
何てことをしてくれた 何てことを
I see... So that's why Jun hates robots...
そっか それで ジュンはロボットのこと…
What do we do, Aki?
どうする アキちゃん
Let's not do it after all...
やっぱり やめようよ
We heard about Doc's robots.
聞いたよ ドクのロボットたちのこと
Let's revive them and Doc's spirits with them too!
うちらで復活させて ドクを勇気づけてあげようよ
But...
でも
Don't you want to cheer him up, Jun?
ジュンだって ドクに元気になってほしいでしょ
That's... true...
それは…そうだけど
But you're scared of robots?
ロボットが怖いから？
And that's why you want to quit the club too?
ロボ部を辞めたい理由も それ？
Wait what?! I didn't know about that!
何それ それは聞いてない
Yashio...
や…八汐君
What's going on, Jun?
どういうこと ジュン
I only joined because I thought it could replace karate.
ロ…ロボ部に入ったのは空手の代わりになればいいなって軽い気持ちで
I could do karate even if I was bad at it.
空手は下手でも続けられたの
I liked it.
好きだったから
But robots...
でも ロボットは
You're scared of them?
やっぱり 怖い？
Then...
だったら
I refuse to accept your resignation!
うちは ジュンの退部を認めない
I won't let you go until you like at least one thing about robots!
ロボットのどこか１つでも好きになってくれるまで絶対に離さない
Let's go! This's a club presidential order!
行くよ これは部長命令だよ
A-Akiho, what--
あ…あき穂ちゃん
電源 入るかな
I wonder if they can be turned on...
あった
Here it is.
Oh...
どうしたの
What is it?
The cords are all cut off.
コードが 切られてる
These robots were killed by Doc himself.
ドク自身の手で殺されたロボットたちか
Where's Yashio?
や…八汐君は
He's inside, fixing Gojiro.
中で 五二郎君の修理してる
He really wants to fix it for some reason.
どうしても 直したいんだって
Ah, hello, brother!
フレー フレー お兄ちゃん
When I fix this one, will you be its operator?
この子が直ったら ジュン オペレーターやってくれないかな
I think only you can fulfill this role.
この役目は ジュンにしかできないと思う
Please, Jun.
お願い ジュン
This should do it.
よし これでＯＫなはず
You're done? You're amazing!
完成ですか すごいです
Now let's turn it on.
じゃ 電源 入れてと
What's that?
何だ
これって…
What?
コン…ニ…チハ
Hello, my name is Yoshiro!
What's that?
何ですか
ボ…クノ ナ…マ…エハ
ヨシ…ロウ
Hey, Kai!
カイ どう？ ちゃんとしゃべるようになったよ
It's talking alright now!
Alright, huh?
I'm your robot friend!
ちゃんとねぇ
オ…トモ…ダチ…
Jun?
ジュンちゃん
ロボ…ットダ…ヨ ネエ
Hello, my name is Yoshiro!
コンニチハ ボクノナマエハ ヨシロウ
That robot...
I'm your robot friend!
あ…あのときの
Aki, turn it off!
アキちゃん ロボット止めて
Huh?
オ…トモダ…チダヨ
Hurry!
早く
You're not my friend!
あなたなんか 友達じゃない
Hey, Jun!
ジュン
Resignation
ついに 突き付けてきたか
Here we go, huh?
I've got stuff to do, so I'm leaving early.
俺 ちょっと用事あるんで 先 行くわ
At a time like this?! What about Jun?
こんなときに 何それ
ジュンは どうすんの
Just leave her be for now.
しばらく様子を見た方がいいって
If you can't do it with force, do it with guile.
押して駄目なら引いてみなってね
I thought that was lovers' wisdom...
それ 恋愛の格言じゃなかった？
Hey Clumsissy! How's my seiken?
下手っぴ姉ちゃん 俺の正拳 どう
I told you not to call me Clumsissy...
下手っぴって言わないでって言ってるでしょ
My kicks are even better!
俺の蹴りの方が すげえって
Hey, make us cookies again!
またお菓子作ってよ
Sure, next time!
うん じゃあ 今度ね
Hurray!
やったぁ
いつもと 雰囲気 違ってたね
You acted different than usual.
Because I'm nervous usually.
Are you really quitting the Robotics Club?
ロボ部 辞めるの
Yeah. I really can't do it.
うん やっぱり 無理
I'm scared of robots.
ロボットは怖いの
I think it'll be easier to cheer up Grandpa without me.
おじいちゃん励ますのも 私はいない方が
I think you're the only one who can cheer Doc up.
ドクを励ませられるのは ジュンちゃんだけだと思うけどね
I doubt that...
そんなことないよ
I avoided him all this time,
私も ずっと避けてきたし
and I'm sure he's still angry at me.
きっと まだ怒ってる 嫌な孫だって思ってるよ
He must hate that I'm his grandchild.
ドクのロボットたち コード切られてたよね
Doc's robots had all their cables cut.
Why do you think he did that?
あれって 何でだと思う
Here. This was on the ground of that shed.
これ あの倉庫に落ちてた
How about you give it another thought?
もうちょっと考えてみれば
You know, robots are the friends of humans!
ロボットはな 人間の友達なんだ
Then I'm their friend too?
じゃあ 私も お友達だね
Yeah!
うん？ ガンつく１の動画？
A video of the GunPro-1?
Yes...
はい
Here, this.
ほら これだ
Excuse me....
す…すいません
Amazing!
It's so big!
So uncool!
だっせ
でけえ
It's huge!
It's huge, but it's uncool!
でけえけど だっせ
It should have some weapons!
武器 ねえのかよ 武器
They're having fun...
楽しそう
Everyone was looking at it like that?
みんな こんなふうに見てたんだ
It's so slow!
おっせ
Do they call that walking?
あれで 歩いてんのかよ
Robots are the friends of humans!
ロボットはな 人間の友達なんだ
Doc blamed himself
ドクは 自分のことを責めてたよ
for arrogantly thinking that robots were the friends of humans.
ロボットは人間の友達だなんて思い上がってたって
But I'd say thinking that is arrogant too.
でも そう思うことこそが思い上がりだと先生は思うね
Remember that.
これ 豆知識な
お前ら
You?
You've shrunk, Doc.
ドク ちっちゃくなっちゃったね
Would you come with us
一緒に来てくれないかな ロボクリニックへ
to the Robot Clinic?
I'm closing that shop.
あの店は もう畳む
It never brought any profits anyway.
もともと もうかりもしねえ店だったしな
Don't say stuff you don't really mean!
そんな 心にもないこと言っちゃ駄目
We know you love it!
本当は大好きなはずだよ
I love Gunvarrel too, so I'll finish it no matter what!
うちも ガンヴァレルが大好きだから 何があっても絶対 完成させる
So...
だから
Anyway, I'm already...
とにかく 俺は もう
But your robots are waiting for you...
ドクのロボットたちが待ってるんだけどなぁ
What did you do?
何をした？ お前ら…まさか
Don't tell me...
Brought back the air of the freshly opened Robot Clinic.
オープン直後のロボクリニックの再現だよ
Are you stupid?! Why would you?!
バカヤロー 何てことを
Let's see how stupid we are in the end.
俺たちがバカかどうか確かめてもらわないとね
We already got you permission to go out.
外出許可は取ってあるから
What now?
どうする
Stop! Please, stop!
やめろ やめてくれ
Someone will get hurt again!
また 傷つけちまう
Someone will make scary memories again!
また 怖い思いをさせちまうだろう
I ruined her...
俺は あの子を
I ruined Jun...
俺が…俺が ジュンを…
Yoshiro?
与四郎
コンニチハ ボクノナマエハ ヨシロウ
Hello, my name is Yoshiro!
I'm your robot friend!
ミンナノ オトモダチロボットダヨ
Hey, let's shake hands!
ネエ アクシュシヨウヨ
ネエ アクシュシヨウヨ フジタノ オジイチャン
Grandpa Fujita!
Why do you know my name?
お前…何で 俺の名前を
He learned it just now.
新しく吹き込んだからだよ
Your son, from your granddaughter.
ドクの息子に ドクの孫娘がね
My granddaughter?
孫娘
Hello, grandpa Fujita!
よろしくね 藤田のおじいちゃん
You'll... forgive me?
俺を…許してくれるのか
I should be the one apologizing...
謝らなきゃいけないのは 私の方だから
I'm sorry, Grandpa...
ごめんね おじいちゃん
I'm still scared,
まだ 少し怖いけど
but I'll get to like Yoshiro and the others...
これから 与四郎君のことも他の子たちのことも
また 好きになっていくから
We'll be friends again...
きっとまた お友達になるから
だから…
So...
Get well soon, Grandpa!
早く元気になって おじいちゃん
ありがとう ありがとう
Thank you... Thank you!
Hurray!
やった
We'll be going home then.
じゃあ うちら 帰るね
Don't do anything crazy; just focus on recovering!
無理しないで ちゃんと治しなよ
お前に心配されるほど老いぼれちゃいねえ
I'm not so old that you'd have to worry about me!
それだけ元気なら 大丈夫か
You should be fine if you can say that.
Hey!
おう お前ら まだあの巨大ロボとやら 造っているのか
You're still building that giant robot, aren't you?
Of course! Nothing's more obvious!
もちろん 当然だよ
Let me see it once when I get outta the hospital.
退院したら 一度 見せてみろ
I'll check how much it rocks.
ロックかどうか 確かめてやる
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
Will overcome even my standards
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
As we climb the stairway to the future
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
Light will always hold this planet together
Lives gather as if by some miracle
Showing the outline of a lively scene
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
The wind blows gently stroking
Turning into a new path
A path that will always
Lead us to this place
Tune in next week too!